

# **GRAHAM STENT (BSc Hons)**

Toronto Tel: (437) 431-7499

E-mail: graystent@gmail.com

# **Key Skills**

AWS EC2, VPC, Lambda, CloudWatch, CloudTrail, IAM, Dynamo DB, S3, API Gateway, Code Build/Deploy/Pipeline CI/CD GitLab, GitHub Actions, Terraform

**Frontend** JavaScript, TypeScript, React, HTML, CSS, Tailwind **API** GraphQL

**Backend** Node.js, Python **Database** MySQL **OS** Linux, Windows

#### **Technical Certifications**

AWS: Solutions Architect -

Associate

Scrum: PSM1 Scrum Master

Kafka: Foundation

**BCS:** Foundation in Business

**Analysis** 

**PRINCE2:** Foundation

**SQL and Database Planning:** Oracle Certification (Foundation)

# **Education**

Leeds Metropolitan University (2006-2009):

Multimedia Technology (BSc Hons): 2:2

# **Interests & Activities**

I have a passion for sports and enjoy spending time playing, and watching them, with friends and family. I'm very fond of the outdoors and nature, and like to explore new places and surrounding wildlife. I also endeavour to keep up to date on current affairs across the globe.

# **GitHub**

github.com/graystent

# Portfolio

graystent-portfolio.vercel.app

# **Personal Profile**

A software engineer with 2 years experience in tech and a decade of experience within the financial services industry, who has moved to Toronto on an open work permit and is looking for a challenging role. I consider myself to be an engaged, resilient problem-solver who strives to do the best and continuously improve my technical capabilities to advance my career. I work successfully under pressure and am extremely adaptable to change and enjoy taking on new challenges. My strong communicative skills enable me to liaise confidently with colleagues in all departments, explaining technical concepts in a comprehensible manner.

### **Work Experience**

Infinity Works part of Accenture – Software Engineer (May 2021 – December 2022)

- Worked in a cross-development team for a large energy company, developing both their mobile and web application using React and React Native.
- Used TypeScript with GraphQL to make requests to the Kraken API to get customer account details.
- AWS CodeBuild, CodeDeploy and CodePipeline was used to deploy the pipelines.
- Applications aligned to Figma design specifications whilst taking into account current development guidelines.
- Attended frequent stakeholder meetings to present progress on own deliverables.
- Led and facilitated workshops and retrospectives to ensure the team were working in the most productive manner to achieve our goals.
- GitHub used for version control.
- Worked on an NHS project as part of small team working on a cloud migration and implementation of a new specialised platform for 'Screening'.
- Following architectural designs and requirements, used React.js with TypeScript, to build user interface where a specific reports could be accessed by the user.
- Python used to query DynamoDB, also used alongside Terraform to implement functionality for the serverless system on AWS.
- Amended IAM policies in Terraform to enable new routing requirements for S3. CloudWatch Logs used to monitor requests and debug issues.
- Used Lambda to retrieve and store data in the required S3 buckets
- Pipelines for builds and commits were managed via GitLab and documentation stored in Confluence.

#### Tech Returners - Journey Into Tech - Full Stack Developer (March 2020 - July 2020)

- 12-week Full Stack Developer boot-camp
- Gained knowledge of programming in JavaScript where Test Driven Development was employed, writing unit tests to ensure my code works and to consolidate learning.
- Developed a web application in React.js using Bootstrap framework along with HTML and CSS. Previously
  acquired JavaScript skills used to add functionality to application and handle events.
- Back end of application deployed using AWS Lambda and RDS was used to link this to MySQL database.

# Royal Bank of Scotland – Quality Checker – (February 2019 – April 2021)

- This role required me to check if the file reviewers have assigned the file to the correct cohort depending on correspondence and interactions with the clients.
- I then check the file reviewer's assessment of account activity, whilst looking for any abnormalities and inconsistencies, to determine the root cause of any possible detriment.
- Where redress is offered I checked the calculations are correctly compiled using the data held on the systems and the data provided by the client.

# New Day Bank – Past Business Review Analyst (December 18 – February 2019)

- This role required me to perform file reviews on historic credit card complaints to conclude if the correct outcome
  was initially achieved.
- This was done by taking an holistic approach to the handling of the compliant, and where a bank error was found, determining the appropriate amount of D&I to be awarded to the customer.
- A bespoke letter was then created and sent to the customer containing active wording to assist the understanding
  of the customer.

# CYBG Group - Quality Assurance (July 16 - December 17) (May 18 - December 18)

- Performed extensive end-to-end quality assurance checks on the handling of mortgage, loan and credit card complaints (personal and business) across both BAU and Remediation workstreams.
- Moved internally to a range of different processes. This included being responsible for checking that the KYC, AML and CDD checks have been completed accurately by the case handlers, from checking the creation of accurate KYC profiles on internal systems to checking research and analysis to find individual beneficiaries for international accounts, the identification of PEPs and AML administration.
- Combined my comprehensive understanding of the multi-faceted processes with my holistic approach to achieve
  a fair customer outcome. I applied risk management in order to measure potential detriment and reported these
  outcomes directly to the FCA.

# PWC - Subject Matter Expert (December 17 - May 18)

- Conducted quality checks of all the Packaged Bank Account cases submitted by case handlers under my supervision against a checklist I created to ensure a fair customer outcome.
- Identified Financial Difficulty and Vulnerability where applicable as per the Bank's and the FCA's guidance.
- Responsible for training and then supporting my team members and providing SME support with their complex cases.
- Identified recurring themes and liaised with management to feedback any themes to the Team Leader and Case Handlers to reduce the amount of errors in cases.

#### Lloyds Banking Group – Quality Checker (October 14 - June 16)

- Detailed checks from receipt to closure for investment, pension and protection product complaints using an expansive range of systems. Ensured all the necessary data was obtained, the correct outcome achieved and the appropriate redress offered via written letter when required.
- My knowledge of procedure, and endeavours to streamline process, was recognised by my participation in the
  cross-site development of the Group's Faster Payment System procedures, where I was instrumental in gathering
  requirements and developing documentation for this new process.

#### Barclays - Sub-Team Leader - General Banking Complaints (January 14 - October 14)

- During this contract, I became the team leader of a specialised financial difficulty team, where I was accountable for work allocation, prioritisation and the reporting of production as well as guiding handlers on complex cases.
- Prior to this I investigated a variety of business and personal complaints ranging from international transactions to fraudulent card activity along with KYC and CDD checks.